<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>media on Logjam</title>
    <link>https://plwg.github.io/tags/media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in media on Logjam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://plwg.github.io/tags/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media is a Loading Spring</title>
      <link>https://plwg.github.io/social-media-is-a-loading-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plwg.github.io/social-media-is-a-loading-spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A system is spring-loaded if it is coiled in a certain direction, positive or negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many have said that social media is an echo chamber. It comes to my
mind that a more appropriate metaphor is a spring being loaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the fictional case of Alice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice posts an opinion on Ditto, a social media platform. Many of
Alice&amp;rsquo;s followers agree with her and start to &amp;ldquo;ditto&amp;rdquo; Alice&amp;rsquo;s post,
pushing it to their follower&amp;rsquo;s timeline. Their followers do the same.
Logically, this process will repeat and propagate itself until it
reaches an equilibrium, &lt;strong&gt;which is the point that every new person
exposed is neutral or negative about Alice&amp;rsquo;s opinion&lt;/strong&gt;. And inevitably
it will reach an end, unless Alice&amp;rsquo;s opinion happens to be a novel
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snow%5FCrash&#34;&gt;neuro-lingustic virus&lt;/a&gt; that is capable of taking over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end result is a highly unpleasant experience for Alice. During the
&amp;ldquo;spring-loading&amp;rdquo; phase, her content spreads far and fast among
supporters. But the end result is that her opinion will eventually get
exposed to an &lt;strong&gt;as-large-as-possible&lt;/strong&gt; surface area of dislike and
ambivalence, often with size many times of her supporter. And because
an attacker can always trace back to Alice, she might suddenly found
that the wind has changed and she is facing a backlash for her
previously popular opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is not a novel observation that people face criticisms and
backlash online, I think the thing worth noting is the spring-like
nature of this phenomenon, that the public opinion will inevitably violently
recoil, and the more popular an online opinion was, the worse the
backlash in the end. Perhaps this is why people are polarized
nowadays. Perhaps Alice&amp;rsquo;s opinion should never have reached so many
disapproving eyeballs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can something be done about this? It probably requires tweaking the
algorithm of these social media platforms such that the speed a piece
of information travels is dampen and the recoil eased. Should it be
done? I don&amp;rsquo;t know. If overdone, I am afraid that it risks creating
real echo chamber where information circulates only internally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
